Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
真っ白な景色にいま誘われて
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
僕は行くよ　まだ見ぬ世界へ
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
迷子のまま旅していた
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
鼠色の空の下
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
日替わりの地図 いくつもの夢が滲んでいた
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
いつかはさ
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
ちっぽけな僕のこの歩幅でも
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
あの雲の向こうまで行けるかな
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
強がって
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
キズついた
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
心透かしたように
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
降り出した
Furidashita
And the raindrops
雨粒たちが
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
乱反射繰り返す
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
真っ直ぐな光が
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
交差して
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
行き先も告げぬまま
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
どこまでも
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
突き抜ける
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
淡い残像　両目に焼きつけて
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
この空の下
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
どんなとこにいても
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
届くはずなんだ
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
まだ見ぬ世界へ
Mada minu sekai e
発煙弾に手榴弾
A smoke bomb and a grenade.
That brat sure is reckless.
無茶をする子供だ
Can you track them by scent?
匂いで追えるか
うん
Yeah.
Hey, MP.
憲兵さん
こいつを安全な所に頼む
Please take her somewhere safe.
Winry, Al's still fighting, so...
ウィンリィ　アルがまだ戦ってるから
オレ　行くよ
I'm going to go.
Sorry.
ごめんな　戻ってきたら全部話す
I'll tell you everything when I get back.
How come... all I can ever do is wait?
なんで　待つことしかできないの
We've taken a girl under protection at 8th District, San Louis Street.
８区　サン·ルイ通りで少女を保護
Apparently, she's a close friend of the Fullmetal Alchemist.
鋼の錬金術師殿の身内らしい
Escort her to Central Headquarters.
中央司令部に護送せよ　繰り返す
I repeat.
８区　サン·ルイ通りで少女を保護
We've taken a girl under protection at 8th District, San Louis Street.
Apparently, she's a close friend of the Fullmetal Alchemist.
I guess it's about time.
そろそろか
Escort her to Central Headquarters.
Go provide them support.
援護に行ってやれ
Roger.
はい
郊外に使える空き家がある
There's a vacant house on the outskirts of town we can use.
Let's meet up here.
ここで落ち合おう
Make sure no one follows you.
つけられるなよ
Yes, sir.
はい
I'll contact you if we make progress.
進展があったら　連絡を入れます
ああ
All right.
現場に出てきちゃダメですよ
You can't come to the scene.
分かってるよ
I know, I know...
So persistent!
しつこい
I'm being driven into a part of town without anyone around...
だんだん　人気のない方へ
Did I fall for their trap?!
はめられたか
うん　スカーか
Was that Scar?
You take care of the other one.
お前は向こうを片づけろ
こっちは私が始末する
I'll put an end to those two.
My left arm is...
左腕が
What's wrong?!
どうした
Young master!
若
I can no longer be of any use to you!
もうお役に立てません
何を言っている
What are you saying?!
If you take me with you, you may fall victim, as well...
私ごときに構っていて
若までも倒れてしまっては
Without his people, there is no King.
民なくしては　王はありえない
But without their King, the people have no place to go.
しかし　王がいなくては民は行き場を失います
You must survive, for the sake of our clan...
我ら一族のためにも
若には生きてもらわねば
I won't leave you!
捨てんぞ
There are plenty of things worth throwing away for a great cause.
大義のために捨てるものなど
いくらでもありましょう
Lan Fan?! What are you planning?!
ランファン　何をする気だ
Don't do it!
やめろ
There's nothing inside your armor, right?
その鎧の中　空だったな
How pitiful!
哀れな
You continue to believe in alchemy
even after being placed in that miserable state?!
そのような不幸な体になって
なお錬金術を信じるのか
この体　不自由なことは沢山ある
This body comes with many inconveniences.
But inconveniences don't make me miserable!
だけど　不自由と不幸はイコールじゃない
哀れに思われる理由はないよ
There's no reason for you to pity me!
兄さんが錬金術でつなぎ止めてくれた命だ
My life was put back together with alchemy by my brother.
今の僕を否定することは
If I deny myself, that would mean
I'm denying brother, along with alchemy.
兄さんを　錬金術を否定することになる
僕は錬金術の可能性を信じてる
I believe in the potential alchemy holds.
I want to believe in it!
信じたい
I see.
そうか
Brother!
兄さん　ウィンリィは
What about Winry?
大丈夫だ
She's fine.
情けねぇ　また泣かせちまった
I'm such an idiot.
I made her cry again.
兄さんはいつも迂闊すぎるんだよ
You're always so careless.
血生臭いところも見られちゃったね
She saw us all covered in blood, too.
ああ
Yeah.
All right, time for act two!
さて　仕切り直しだ
Found you!!!
見つけたぁ
The Ishbalan!
イシュヴァール人
You're...
貴様は
That tattoo!
あの入れ墨
人造人間
A Homunculus!
Lin!
リン
Run!
逃げろ
頑丈なワイヤー
Get me a sturdy wire!
R-Right!
お おう
The fact your regeneration ability is so powerful became your downfall!
再生力がありすぎるのがあだとなったな
Your own meat that expands from within the wire will end up binding you tighter!
内側から盛り上がる自分の肉で自ら締めつけられる
捕ったぞ　人造人間
Got you, Homunculus!
Well played.
見事なり
I outwitted you, monster!
出し抜いてやったぞ　化け物め
What? A Homunculus?
なんだ　人造人間だと
乗せて　逃げるわよ
Get him on!
We're making a run for it!
Hey, wait a minute Lieute-
あっ　待ったホーク
しっ
H-Hang on!
ちょっ　ちょっと待ってよ
Al!
アル
憲兵が見てる　無関係を装え
The military police are watching.
Pretend like you don't know them.
They ran!
逃げたぞ　スカーを捕らえろ
Capture Scar!
はっ
Yes, sir!
The Colonel isn't the nicest guy around, but he's trustworthy.
大佐はいけ好かねぇヤツだが　信用はできる
それより今は
But more importantly...
スカーを捕まえるぞ　アル
We need to capture Scar, Al!
うん
Right!
Multiple crimes, including the murder of the Rockbells!
ロックベル夫妻殺害の件　その他もろもろ
出るところへ出て裁いてもらう
You'll pay for those crimes!
無事ですか　下僕さん
Are you all right, Mister Servant?
我が恩人ヨキさんの下僕さんに何をするんですか
How dare you do something like this to the servant of my savior, Yoki!
この豆男
You pipsqueak!
んだと　この豆女
What did you say?! Speak for yourself!
Who is that child?!
なんだあの子供は
Little girl, get away from him!
お嬢ちゃん　離れて　危ないから
It's dangerous!
多勢に無勢
We're far outnumbered...
ここは退却です
We ought to retreat!
Just what the hell was that alchemy?!
なんだ　あの錬金術
離れた場所に錬成を
She performed transmutations from a distance?!
This way.
こっちです
くそっ　見えねぇ
Dammit, I can't see a thing!
Scar!!!
スカー
I've already heard about you, Lin Yao.
あなたのことは聞いてるわ　リン·ヤオ
このまままっすぐ隠れ家に行くわね
We're heading straight to our hideout.
待った
Wait! I left a comrade. Pick her up for me!
仲間が一人いる　拾ってくれ
Huh?
ダメよ　そんな余裕ないわ
No, we don't have time!
頼む　今死にそうになってるんだ
I'm begging you! She's in critical condition!
オレが迎えに行くのを待っている
She's waiting for me to come and get her!
手早く頼むわよ
Make it quick.
あの女は確かマスタングの
If I recall, that woman is Mustang's...
やってくれたな　若造
You've gone and done it now, youngster.
オレも　あんな目を
So even I had those eyes...
どこまでいっても　憎しみは憎しみしか生まんのか
No matter how far along we've come,
hatred only brings about more hatred...
これで出血は止まったと思います
That should have stopped the bleeding.
すまん
Thanks.
だんな
Master!
憲兵隊が近くまで来ている
The military police are just around the corner!
逃げた方が
We should run...
ヤツは傷を負っている
Our target is injured!
まだそんなに遠くには逃げてはいないはずだ
He couldn't have gotten far!
しらみつぶしに捜せ
Search thoroughly!
Yes, sir!
だんな　早く早く
Master!
Hurry! Hurry!
シャオメイ　逃げる
Shao May, we have to-
Huh?
あれ
拾っちゃった
I found something.
お前な　この非常時に何拾ってんだよ
You! Is this really the time to be picking stuff up?!
だってあの騒ぎの中独りぼっちだったんだよ
But it was all alone in the midst of that!
お前はいつもいつも
You always do this!
野良猫拾ってはこっそり体ん中で飼いやがって
You once picked up a stray cat and raised it inside your armor without telling me!
捨ててこい
Get rid of that thing!
兄さんの人でなし
You're horrible!
こんなにおとなしいのに
Look how tame it is!
大丈夫　落ち着いて
It's okay. Relax.
どうぞ　こちらです
Please. This way.
どうも
Thanks.
中に入っててね
Stay inside, okay?
ウィンリィ
Winry!
やあ　鋼の錬金術師君
How's it going, Fullmetal Alchemist?
ブラッドレイ大総統
Führer President Bradley.
どうして
Why are you...
君たちの幼なじみが保護されていると聞いたものでね
I heard your childhood friend was under guard here.
大切な人材の身内だ
She's a person close to one of my valued, talented alchemists.
丁重に扱わなければな
I have to treat her courteously.
ではお嬢さん　私は失礼するよ
Well then, young lady, I'll be taking my leave.
あっ　はい　どうも
Okay. Thanks for everything.
素直ないい子だ
She's a good, honest girl.
大切にしたまえよ
Treat her with care, okay?
エド
Ed.
約束よ　父さんと母さんのこと　全部教えて
You promised.
Tell me everything you know about Mom and Dad.
そう
I see...
最期まで　人のために尽くしてたんだね
So they were doing their best to help people until the very end...
でも　やっぱり生きて帰って来てほしかった
But...
...I still wish they could have come back alive...
私は待つことしかできない
All I can do... is wait.
Oh, perfect timing!
あっ　ちょうどよかった
ロックベル様にお電話が入っております
There's a call for Miss Rockbell.
私
For me?
もしもし
Hello?
ガーフィールさん
Mr. Garfield?
ごめんねぇウィンリィちゃん
Sorry, Winry.
私だけでどうにかしようと思ったんだけど
I was hoping to take care of everything myself, but...
ウィンリィちゃんはまだ帰って来ないの
Is Winry still not back?!
Look at this! Only Winry can fix this!
これ見てよ　ウィンリィちゃん以外には直せないでしょ
Your customers really miss you!
あなたのお客がもう皆うるさくって
早く帰っとくれよ　ウィンリィちゃん
Please come back soon, Winry!
ウィンリィおねえちゃん
Winry?
テツ君
Tetsu?
Please, come back soon!
おねえちゃん　早く帰って来てよ
My foot feels so much better when you operate on it rather than Mr. Garfield!
ガーフィールさんより
おねえちゃんに見てもらった方が足の調子がいいんだ
ウィンリィちゃんこの前かたどりした足の外装
Winry, I need you to finish off the exterior for my leg as soon as possible!
早いとこ頼むよ
My arm, too!
おいらの腕も頼むぜ
No, I'm first!
いいや　こっちが先だ
早く会いたいよ
I want to see you soon!
バカヤロ　ウィンリィちゃんは皆のものだ
You idiot, Winry belongs to everybody!
違ぇねぇ
That's right!
ごめんね　すぐ戻るね
Sorry... I'll be back soon.
待っててね
Please wait for me.
頑張るから　頑張るから
I'll do... I'll do my best...
ありがとうね
Thanks.
あの時　止めてくれてありがとうね
Thanks for stopping me back then.
私を待ってくれる人たちがいるんだよね
There are people who are waiting for me.
その人たちに　顔向けできなくなるところだった
I was close to doing something that would make me unable to face them.
ウィンリィ
Winry...
エド　機械鎧の手入れ忘れないでね
Ed, don't forget to maintain your automail!
Y-You got it!
今度　いい磨き油送るね　アル
I'll send you some good polishing oil sometime, Al.
Okay!
死なないでね
Please don't die.
We won't.
Got it.
今度　お前を
Next time I make you-
Huh? What?
えっ　何　聞こえないよ
I can't hear you.
兄さん　待ってよ
Brother?
Wait!
じゃあね　ウィンリィ
Bye, Winry.
O-Okay.
Geez...
ちょっとエド　なんて言ったのよ
Hey, Ed!
What did you say?!
今度お前を泣かせる時は　嬉し泣きだ
Next time I make you cry, it'll be with tears of joy!
絶対アルと二人で元に戻って
Al and I will get our bodies back for sure, and we'll make you cry tears of joy!
嬉し泣きをさせてやるからな
覚えてろ
You'd better remember!
オレに手足をくれ
Give me an arm and a leg.
１年だ
One year.
We have no place to return now.
もう　後戻りできねぇな
なんでお前が泣くんだよ
Why are you  crying?
そっか
Oh, I get it...
私　ほれてたんだ
I... fell in love with him...
大佐
Colonel!
乗りたまえ
Get in.
ちっ
重傷者がいる　医者が必要だ
There's someone seriously wounded.
We need a doctor.
またヤバい橋か
Doing dangerous things again?
このクソガキ
You stupid brat.
確か　あなたには家族がいたはずだ
If I recall, you have family.
If it'll cause trouble, you don't have to do it.
迷惑なら　断ってくれていい
道具持ってくるから　待ってろ
I'll go bring some instruments, so hang tight.
いいのか
Is it okay?
イシュヴァールから帰ってすぐに妻とは別れた
I divorced my wife soon after I came back from Ishbal.
腕をぶった斬ったまま下水道を歩いたぁ
You walked in the sewers with your arm cut off?!
破傷風になっても知らんぞ
I wouldn't be surprised if you got tetanus!
最近　死体の相手しかしてないからな
I've only dealt with corpses lately.
ちと荒っぽいぞ
So I may be a bit rough.
すまん
I'm sorry...
勘違いするなよ
Don't get the wrong idea.
話を持ちかけたのはこっちだ
We're the ones who offered to help.
利害が一致したから協力しただけだ
We only worked with you guys because we had a common interest.
不老不死なんて求めるからには
I'm seeking something so great as immortality.
それなりの犠牲は覚悟して国を出てきている
I was prepared for the worst when I left my country.
いや　足りなかった
No... I wasn't prepared enough.
オレよりも　ランファンの方が覚悟があった
Lan Fan was more prepared than I was.
大丈夫
Are you all right?
Is there anything we can do for you?
何かできることあるか
貴様のトラップ　悪くなかった
Your trap wasn't half bad...
だがもう使えない
But I can't use it anymore...
I need a replacement arm.
代わりの腕が必要なんだ
ああ　いい機械鎧技師紹介するぜ
Sure!
I'll introduce you to an awesome automail mechanic!
国軍大佐　ロイ·マスタングだ
I'm Colonel Roy Mustang of the military.
シン国皇帝第１２子　リン·ヤオ
I'm Lin Yao, twelfth prince of the Xing Dynasty.
医者を手配してくれて感謝する
I'm grateful that you found us a doctor.
こちらこそ　マリア·ロスの件では世話になった
You helped us out by helping Maria Ross, as well.
それと　今回の件でもな
And this thing, too.
おい　なんだあれは
Hey, what the hell is that?
グラトニーと呼ばれる　人造人間だ
He's a homunculus by the name of Gluttony.
ホ
Ho-
どうやらこいつは軍上層部の一部と繋がりがあるらしい
Apparently, this guy has some sort of connection with a portion of the upper echelons of the military.
一部だと　それどころじゃないぞ
"A portion"?!
You have no idea!
King Bradley.
キング·ブラッドレイ
あいつも人造人間の可能性がある
There's a possibility he's a Homunculus, as well.
眼帯の下　眼球にウロボロスの入れ墨があった
He had a tattoo of Ouroboros on his eye underneath his eyepatch.
グラトニーと一緒になってオレたちを追い詰めてきた
He and Gluttony both came after us.
まさか
No way...
国のトップが人造人間
The top man of the country is a Homunculus?!
ただ　ブラッドレイには
But...
...Bradley did not give off a sense of not being a human, like Gluttony did.
グラトニーのような人ならざる人の気配がない
普通の人間の気配と一緒なんだ
He feels the same as an ordinary human.
だったら
Then...
第一大総統が人造人間なら　息子さんはどうなるのさ
First of all, if the Führer President is a Homunculus, what about his son?!
人造人間は生殖能力がないって本に書いてあったよ
I read in a book that Homunculi are unable to reproduce!
No.
いや　息子のセリムは養子だ
His son, Selim, was adopted.
大総統の血を分けた子供じゃない
He doesn't carry the blood of the Führer President.
化け物か人か　いずれにせよ
A monster or a human...
Whichever it may be, now it's easier to drag him out of his position.
大総統のイスから引きずり下ろしやすくなったな
まずはこいつから情報を引き出す
We'll get information out of this guy, first.
賢者の石も頂こう
Let's take his philosopher's stone, too.
部下の治療に使えるかもしれん
I may be able to use it to heal my man.
おいおいおい　ランファンが腕を失ってまで手に入れた
Hey, hey, hey!
Lan Fan lost her arm to obtain that!
不老不死の手がかりだ
We're taking that back to Xing!
シンに持ち帰らせてもらう
ちょっと待てよ
Hang on! We've been searching for a way to get our bodies back for a long time, too!
こっちだって元の体に戻る方法を長いこと探してるんだ
持ち逃げは許さねぇ
I won't allow you to take it for yourself!
そうだ　リン　君は不法入国だ
That's right.
Lin, you're an illegal immigrant.
ああ もうついていけねぇ
I can't stand this!
マスタングさんよ　オレは帰らせてもらうぞ
Mustang, I'm going home.
マスタング
Mustang...
ラスト殺した　マスタング大佐
Colonel Mustang... who killed Lust!
ロイ·マスタング
Roy Mustang!!!
何
What...
Let it all out, Let it all out
I don't have to act tough, right?
強がらなくていいんだね
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
誰かが描いてった
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
壁の落書きの花が　揺れる
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
自分らしさなんて, 誰もわからないよ
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
長い長い道の途中で
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
失くしたり, 拾ったり,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
急に寂しくなって, 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
涙も　痛みも　星に変えよう
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
明日を照らす　灯りをともそう
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
小さな手かざして　ふたりで作ろう
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
星屑を　強く光る永遠を探そう
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
さよなら　いつかは来るかもしれない
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
季節はそれでも巡り巡ってく
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
小さく迷っても　歩いてく
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
君と歩いてく
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
それだけは変わらないでいようね
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
善意と好意の笑みの裏
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
What is hidden behind the smile of goodwill and kindness?
何が隠れる森の中
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
探る手段は慎重に
One must be discreet in order to dig further.
進む暗中模索の走り
They move forward and run about, not knowing what to do.
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
第二十四話　腹の中
Episode 24, Inside the Belly.
迂闊に飛び込めば
If you leap in carelessly, all that awaits is a sea of darkness.
待っているのは黒い闇